[{"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c58e", "question": "Eastern Diamondback, Massasauga and Timber are species of what animal?", "answer": "Rattlesnake", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339610", "question": "What does Arnold Schwarzenegger pretend to do for a living in the movie \"True Lies\"?", "answer": "Computer salesman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2ac", "question": "Whose scary movie character has the real name of Charles Lee Ray?", "answer": "Chucky\u00a0", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c359", "question": "On which planet did the spacecraft Venus 8 land in 1972?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b8e", "question": "Who played the role of Colonel Kurtz in the movie \"Apocalypse Now\"?", "answer": "Marlon Brando", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60121ab563c99d48cd169b06", "question": "What were clocks missing before 1577?", "answer": "Minute hands", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad9da99e748bb36357acdd4", "question": "What is the largest animal to ever live?", "answer": "The Blue whale", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c356", "question": "What is odontophobia the fear of?", "answer": "Dentistry", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6014c95ffbde8045e48466eb", "question": "What is ferret saying when he performs a \"weasel war dance\"?", "answer": "\"Come play with me\" -- They sleep 15 hours per day.  When they are awake, they want to have fun and play with their human friends.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c9f", "question": "In \"The Wizard of Oz\", what was Dorothy's uncle's name?", "answer": "Henry", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133895e", "question": "What was Cinderella's real name?", "answer": "Ella", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bada", "question": "What brand of cat food was advertised by Morris the Cat?", "answer": "9 Lives", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff213f431a458464a93c453", "question": "\"Occam\u2019s Razor\" posits that what kind of idea is usually most accurate?", "answer": "Simplest", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad47", "question": "Harry Truman was known as \"the Haberdasher\" because of what?", "answer": "His previous occupation", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ec247b8dc25ca9e12ef638", "question": "Cinnabar is the most common source for which compound?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b58a", "question": "Which country invented the sauna?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b32342bbf195a31e15d73a3", "question": "What are a Galliard, Sarabande, and Courante?", "answer": "Dance types", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc28", "question": "What year was Martha Stewart born?", "answer": "1941", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d03", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Barney Fife?", "answer": "Sheriff Andy Taylor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339988", "question": "What 1987 movie marked the first big screen starring role for Bruce Willis?", "answer": "Blind Date", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395e8", "question": "In The Simpsons episode, \"Principal Charming,\" who does Skinner fall in love with?", "answer": "Patty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c060", "question": "What are the three colors of the flag of the United Kingdom?", "answer": "Red, White and Blue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59cdb20f65ff7d326b622a70", "question": "What is the study of rocks and their formation called?", "answer": "Petrology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59d185873b17032616b59100", "question": "When was Nescafe's instant coffee first launched?", "answer": "1938", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5cd", "question": "In the game \"Battleship\", how many hits does it take to sink an aircraft carrier?", "answer": "5", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef616e6ce05a3942286e52", "question": "Which basketball move was banned from 1967-1976?", "answer": "Slam dunk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "591c37a4815febcc896f9272", "question": "What Turkish city has spread to both sides of the Bosphorus Strait?", "answer": "Istanbul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e14cfe83fe1f2a824b93", "question": "What best describes Germany\u2019s standard invasion strategy at the beginning of World War II?", "answer": "Attack with a combination of speed and overwhelming force (blitzkrieg)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff2114f31a458464a93c440", "question": "Emily Bronte\u2019s \"Wuthering Heights\" famously described which English naturescape?", "answer": "Yorkshire moorlands", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339833", "question": "What movie, set in Vietnam, won an Oscar for \"Best Picture\" in 1987?", "answer": "Platoon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bca9", "question": "What drink is made from fermented honey, yeast and water?", "answer": "Mead", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c98e", "question": "What is Lepidopterology the study of?", "answer": "Moths and butterflies", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fc2f025cee580c7f8fd1e4a", "question": "What famous general was nicknamed \"Old blood and guts\" by his men?", "answer": "General George S. Patton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b1e", "question": "Who wrote the book \"The Wonderful Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "L. Frank Baum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ae9", "question": "Who wrote the lyrics of the Christmas carol \"Silent Night\"?", "answer": "Joseph Mohr", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b43", "question": "What publication uses the motto \"America's Finest News Source\"?", "answer": "The Onion", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6016021cfe83fe1f2a824c63", "question": "Which Christian holiday is directly related to the observance of the March equinox?", "answer": "Easter is traditionally celebrated on the Sunday after the first full moon that occurs on or after the March equinox.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a477", "question": "How many South American Countries does the equator pass through?", "answer": "Three", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b71b", "question": "What do South Africans decorate at Christmas time with cotton, wool and tinsel?", "answer": "Their windows", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad9dc69e748bb36357acddd", "question": "What 21st-century US presidential candidate had a spouse who was president of two colleges?", "answer": "Bernie Sanders", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a029", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", who did Peter force to become a professional boxer?", "answer": "Lois", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133946f", "question": "What was Toula's wedding present from her parents in the movie \"My Big Fat Greek Wedding\"?", "answer": "A house", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "591c3729815febcc896f926e", "question": "What is a group of mallards in flight called?", "answer": "A Sord", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133916a", "question": "Who wrote and directed the movie \"American Graffiti\"?", "answer": "George Lucas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f09", "question": "What author created the character of Travis McGee?", "answer": "John D. MacDonald", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e2", "question": "What was the maximum number of characters that one can use in a Twitter tweet before they were doubled in 2017?", "answer": "140", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca6d", "question": "Quercus is the Latin name of what tree?", "answer": "Oak", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f8", "question": "What Olympic field event's two main styles are the glide and the spin?", "answer": "Shot put's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab0f", "question": "Which peninsula is Greece located on?", "answer": "Balkan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7cc7a877e98cb97778a26", "question": "Where was Breakneck Ridge in World War II?", "answer": "The Philippines", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd2d48f2596a59cbdfbd3a5", "question": "What is the main substance found in bones?", "answer": "Collagen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf0f", "question": "Where does the famous \"running of the bulls\" take place?", "answer": "Pamplona", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa72", "question": "Frankfort is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Kentucky", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c14e", "question": "Porphyrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "The color purple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c584", "question": "By what common household name is sodium chloride better known?", "answer": "Salt", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a4d9b5608b8581f80b092c4", "question": "Which key button did Apple remove in its flagship iPhone X model?", "answer": "The Home button", "category": "general"}, {"id": "592eb0f6f83302ff91e464a2", "question": "What company makes the Vince Lombardi Trophy?", "answer": "Tiffany & Co.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b29a", "question": "What US politician was named for Julius Caesar?", "answer": "J. C. Watts", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff141c0b0ee8c595b6d39a6", "question": "Which Dutch artist painted \"Girl with a Pearl Earring\"?", "answer": "Vermeer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe36ce40ada16518afdc03e", "question": "What car company makes the Econoline van", "answer": "Ford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a0f", "question": "What was the name of Paul and Jamie\u2019s dog on the TV show \"Mad About You\"?", "answer": "Murray", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e3f7d05cb9e8bda6821370", "question": "What year did Beethoven finish composing Symphony No. 9?", "answer": "1824", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ec2b24043630d44e5be228e", "question": "The Kentucky Derby, Preakness Stakes and Belmont Stakes comprise which series?", "answer": "Triple Crown", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339224", "question": "Who celebrated is 111th birthday during \"The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring?\"", "answer": "Bilbo Baggins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecd3bcec223966ae8f88c8", "question": "In what movie does Gloria Swanson say, \"All right, Mr. DeMille, I'm ready for my close-up\"?", "answer": "\"Sunset Boulevard\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393c6", "question": "What Hollywood director had a small role in the movie \"The Blues Brothers\"?", "answer": "Steven Spielberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ac9", "question": "In what year did the French author Charles Perrault die?", "answer": "1703", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a618", "question": "The underground lake, The Lost Sea, is located in which US state's Craighead Caverns?", "answer": "Tennessee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5cefc077948005ec986edcdb", "question": "Who is the second member of the group LOONA to debut? ", "answer": "Hyunjin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c797", "question": "Which scientist is credited with being the first one to isolate DNA material?", "answer": "Friedrich Miescher", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea49d6ff048f679a45abbc", "question": "What part of the plant gets water and nutrients to the rest of the plant?", "answer": "Stem", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4eed806d333868d34d776", "question": "Where did the croissant originate?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b091e662d71a53650fca", "question": "What part of New York did Vito Corleone grow up in?", "answer": "After Vito flees Sicily, he finds shelter with the Abbandando family in Little Italy, New York.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c281", "question": "What is a shadow clock?", "answer": "A sundial", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5be580f65415ba52ed6f0abc", "question": "Which Canadian Prime Minister was responsible for introducing the Canada Pension Plan?", "answer": "Lester B. Pearson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c794", "question": "In science, what does the abbreviation DNA stand for?", "answer": "Deoxyribonucleic acid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339346", "question": "What TV show did Tom Hanks appear on for two seasons?", "answer": "Bosom Buddies", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a5", "question": "What is the name of Doc Brown's very clever dog in the \"Back to the Future\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Einstein", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b73d", "question": "According to the Dewey Decimal System, library books numbered in the 500s are part of what category?", "answer": "Science", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a36e", "question": "What is the capital of Syria?", "answer": "Damascus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5b2", "question": "How many rings are there on a five-zone archery target?", "answer": "Four", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a240", "question": "What is the first name of Inspector Morse in the TV series by the same name?", "answer": "Endeavour", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c256", "question": "What is the SI physical unit of dynamic viscosity?", "answer": "Pascal-second", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133929c", "question": "Apart from the piano, what other musical instrument does Dr. Sheldon Cooper from the TV show \"The Big Band Theory\"?", "answer": "The theramin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e3", "question": "Which company created the slogan \"We'll leave the light on for you\"?", "answer": "Motel 6", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338afe", "question": "Which character killed Richard Cory?", "answer": "Himself", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a76d", "question": "What lake in Oregon was created about 7,000 years ago by the eruption of Mount Mazama?", "answer": "Crater Lake", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd3a", "question": "What poker hand are you holding if you have \"two fish-hooks\"?", "answer": "A pair of jacks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c4c3fbde8045e48466a1", "question": "What is the function of the skin patches (warts) on a warthog's face?", "answer": "Protection during fights -- Like many animals, male warthogs battle for dominance during mating season.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a733", "question": "The Rio Grande River flows in what body of water?", "answer": "Gulf of Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab13f6baab681b09292170", "question": "What car manufacturer was the first to mass-produce and equip a production vehicle with a V4 engine?", "answer": "Lancia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5db03e6caa1c9af2684d79a4", "question": "What is the common name for CH3COOH?", "answer": "Acetic acid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60062a82c9d816e292245c19", "question": "What artist created a 43 ft sculpture of a West Highland White Terrier puppy?", "answer": "Jeff Koons (He was commissioned to create the piece for Arolsen Castle in Germany.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c02", "question": "Tony Pastor is credited with popularizing what form of theater in the early 1880s?", "answer": "Vaudeville", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff20ff931a458464a93c43a", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Nostromo\"?", "answer": "Robert Conrad", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad7ea43b24f84e0b9f9ffd2", "question": "What is a figure with eight equal sides called?", "answer": "Regular Octagon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c34d", "question": "The strength of prescription eyeglasses is measured in what unit?", "answer": "Diopters", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0fb", "question": "Who was the first Canadian-born boxer to win the heavyweight championship?", "answer": "Tommy Burns", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcc0", "question": "Who met longtime best friend Gayle King in 1976?", "answer": "Oprah Winfrey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aab9", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Iceland?", "answer": "Gyrfalcon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a71f", "question": "Kazumura Cave is the longest cave in which state?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefa6f06ce05a3942286ecd", "question": "In the film \"Fargo\", Jerry Lundegaard was captured by the police in what city?", "answer": "Bismarck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a25a", "question": "In what country did Alfred Hitchcock die?", "answer": "United States", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b386", "question": "Which country was known as British Honduras prior to 1973?", "answer": "Belize", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a85a", "question": "Which US state is the third largest state by land area?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399bc", "question": "How many episodes of \"The Beverly Hillbillies\" were made?", "answer": "274", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad19", "question": "What bird did Benjamin Franklin favor for America's national emblem?", "answer": "The turkey", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133988a", "question": "What instrument is Questlove most famous for playing?", "answer": "Drums", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601218b963c99d48cd169af7", "question": "In Swedish, what is \"entrance\" and \"driveway\", respectively?", "answer": "\"Infart\" and \"Uppfart\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bda7", "question": "Whose emblem came from a sketch Lamar Hunt drew on a napkin in 1963?", "answer": "The Kansas City Chiefs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4bf", "question": "In medicine, what does the abbreviation LASIK stand for?", "answer": "Laser-Assisted In Situ Keratomileusis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60062a19c9d816e292245c13", "question": "What Flemish Baroque painter is well known for his Counter-Reformation altarpieces?", "answer": "Peter Paul Rubens -- He was a proponent of an extravagant Baroque style that emphasized movement, colour, and sensuality.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c25e", "question": "What is a wallaby?", "answer": "A kangaroo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "591c36ad815febcc896f9269", "question": "Who runs the \"Leftorium\"?", "answer": "Ned Flanders", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb5f", "question": "What coastal Atlantic US state has \"The Shag\" as their official state dance?", "answer": "South Carolina", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338da2", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Brown?", "answer": "Thomas Hughes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8f9bb01dd7bf43be5e84d", "question": "What was football legend Joe Namath's nickname?", "answer": "Broadway Joe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af35", "question": "What was the name of the political police in Nazi Germany?", "answer": "Gestapo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338af6", "question": "Which character killed Albus Dumbledore?", "answer": "Severus Snape", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e36", "question": "What game show host took his stage name from the college in his West Virginia hometown?", "answer": "Peter Marshall", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a823", "question": "What Caribbean island nation's name comes from the Portuguese word meaning \"bearded ones\"?", "answer": "Barbados", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6998f20565ad31a57c748", "question": "What were the names of the Doberman Pinschers on \"Magnum P.I.\"?", "answer": "Zeus and Apollo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4bba49076251badbeac7", "question": "How many rooms are there in Buckingham Palace (total number)?", "answer": "775 -- It includes 19 State rooms, 92 offices, 52 Royal and guest bedrooms, 188 bedrooms for staff and 78 bathrooms.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391c4", "question": "In which movie does Al Pacino play a character named Ricky Roma?", "answer": "Glengarry Glen Ross", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b27b", "question": "What African region has been ravaged by militia called the Janjaweed?", "answer": "Darfur", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a050", "question": "Mark Waters directed which 2004 hit film starring Lindsay Lohan?", "answer": "Mean Girls", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3867c73aa70ea0b70ad0", "question": "Which US state gets its name from a made-up word?", "answer": " Idaho (Mining lobbyist George M. Willing told Congress \"Idaho\" was a Native American phrase for \"gem of the mountains\". He made it up.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdabc0f0b8cce1e6fda705b", "question": "Which common necktie knot produces a solid, large triangular shape?", "answer": "Windsor", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc1408469bb8041d07a083", "question": "A ganache is a combination of cream and what?", "answer": "Chocolate", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398ae", "question": "What movie followed the adventures of Marty McFly?", "answer": "Back to the Future", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59bb2a52c9bff04efae6d75f", "question": "What is the birthname of author George Orwell?", "answer": "Eric Arthur Blair", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4cf", "question": "What kind of stone is the Taj Mahal made of?", "answer": "Marble", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390f7", "question": "What is the first name of writer H. G. Wells?", "answer": "Herbert", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adc8", "question": "What was the capital city of Portugal between the years 1808 and 1821?", "answer": "Rio de Janeiro", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ad5", "question": "What year did Andy Warhol die?", "answer": "1987", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59068058ff9c0647b50a808b", "question": "Who wrote and directed the 1973 film \"Westworld\" that was used as the basis for the 2016 HBO TV series by the same name?", "answer": "Michael Crichton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afad", "question": "Off of which European coastline was the \"Battle of Trafalgar\" fought?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b22b", "question": "Gandhi's famous march to Dandi in 1930 was an act to protest against Great Britain's tax on what?", "answer": "Salt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338af2", "question": "Pablo Picasso was one of the suspects questioned when what item was stole in Paris in 1911?", "answer": "The Mona Lisa", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a4d983708b8581f80b092ae", "question": "What game won the Game of the Year award at The Game Awards 2017?", "answer": "The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b3d7e662d71a53650fe4", "question": "What is the opening section of an opera called?", "answer": "The overture", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5c90d3ff52800b05cac20f1a", "question": "What is the real name of the DC character Deathstroke?", "answer": "Slade Wilson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fa1", "question": "What TV show's cops operate out of a converted church they call \"the Barn\"?", "answer": "The Shield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff214f631a458464a93c45a", "question": "What is the name of the US President's official guest house?", "answer": "Blair House", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339729", "question": "Which musical instrument was Buddy Rich best known for playing?", "answer": "Drums", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69dc420565ad31a57c77c", "question": "Which president\u2019s mother was a wrestler?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4b6", "question": "What process includes the following phases: prophase, metaphase, anaphase, and telophase?", "answer": "Cell mitosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd969ce23c87fd04dd15e0d", "question": "What was Thomas Edison's nickname?", "answer": "The Wizard of Menlo Park", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd18", "question": "In the UK, what is called a \"courgette\"?", "answer": "A zucchini", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5aab2e5258d116dab4aecb3d", "question": "In Olympic competitions, what are the heights of the diving boards?", "answer": "3 and 10 meters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c221", "question": "What is the name of Canada's national anthem?", "answer": "O Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffe4b7b47818f5674af01b1", "question": "From which novel is this quote \"I\u2019m the most terrific liar you ever saw in your life. It\u2019s awful.\"?", "answer": "\"The Catcher in the Rye\" (The main character, Holden Caulfield, fittingly says this early in the novel while describing himself.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abe8", "question": "What year did Guatemala declare its independence from Spain?", "answer": "1821", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "591c3721815febcc896f926d", "question": "What is a group of mallards in flight called?", "answer": "A Sord", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339221", "question": "Which two artists formed the band \"Wham!\"?", "answer": "George Michael and Andrew Ridgeley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f72bba9e54d890926f6ed", "question": "Six Flags, the famous Texas amusement park, was named after what?", "answer": "The six governments that have ruled Texas -- Specifically, France, Spain, Mexico, the Confederacy, Texas and the U.S.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b572", "question": "What is Grappa?", "answer": "An Alcoholic Drink", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a77a", "question": "What city serves as the capital of Northern Ireland?", "answer": "Belfast", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe36e5c0ada16518afdc044", "question": "What temperature should you not exceed when melting chocolate?", "answer": "120 F or 49 C", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a415", "question": "What US city is home to the annual \"All-American Soap Box Derby\"?", "answer": "Akron, Ohio", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a02a", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", Franz Gutentag was once what?", "answer": "A Nazi war criminal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339553", "question": "Who played Mork and Mindy's baby?", "answer": "Jonathan Winters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59008f30cf842fa4c4ba96b9", "question": "Italian painter Jacopo Comin is better known as who?", "answer": "Tintoretto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea364aff048f679a45ab0b", "question": "Carrots are a good source of which vitamin?", "answer": "A", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d52", "question": "What year was author J. K. Rowling born in?", "answer": "1965", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391be", "question": "In which film did Paul Newman play a crime boss named John Rooney?", "answer": "Road to Perdition", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c09f", "question": "How many wine gallons does a \"half pipe\" barrel contain?", "answer": "63", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad3d", "question": "Which archaeologist discovered King Tut's tomb in 1922?", "answer": "Howard Carter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc32", "question": "What color is the saffron spice?", "answer": "Yellow-orange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f9f4054af848b908361b86d", "question": "What food item has a warning label reading: \"Do not use with fresh or frozen pineapple, kiwi, gingerroot, papaya, figs or guava\" or a similar variation?", "answer": "Jell-O", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca1d", "question": "Almonds are members of what family?", "answer": "Rose", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c20c877e98cb97778984", "question": "Where can you find \"Aphrodite's Rock\"?", "answer": "Cyprus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef5be76ce05a3942286e1a", "question": "Flora, Fauna, and Merryweather are fairies in which Disney classic?", "answer": "\"Sleeping Beauty\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ad", "question": "What does the \"PJ\" stand for in the name PJ Harvey?", "answer": "Polly Jean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59008c0ecf842fa4c4ba969d", "question": "Mysophobia is the irrational fear of what?", "answer": "Contamination", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339573", "question": "What musical artist sang, It's the Most Wonderful Time of the Year?", "answer": "Andy Williams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60062a43c9d816e292245c16", "question": "What American artist is known for paintings of flags?", "answer": "Jasper Johns is an American painter, sculptor and printmaker associated with Abstract expressionism, Neo-Dada, and Pop art.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a9e970e7ccba3ffe45786f7", "question": "What is the fear of bees known as?", "answer": "Melissophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "590499a3cf93664eb1048694", "question": "Who hosted the 2007 Brit Awards?", "answer": "Russell Brand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b90", "question": "What Kenny Rogers song title is his mother's first name?", "answer": "Lucille", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c3e9a43ebfabb9c85d8a979", "question": "The meat pie, Tourtiere, originated in which country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bbd4d3c00d154d7af00b8d4", "question": "In the music video \"Opposites Attract\", what is the name of the cat Paula Abdul dances with?", "answer": "MC Skat Kat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e9f", "question": "What was the name of Puff the Magic Dragon's homeland?", "answer": "Honalee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e95f77ccba3ffe45786e6", "question": "Whose autobiography was entitled \"The Sport of Queens\"?", "answer": "Dick Francis'", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6e0", "question": "What is the capital of Florida?", "answer": "Tallahassee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133964b", "question": "What kind of animal is the title character in the 1995 movie \"Babe\"?", "answer": "Pig", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c3c", "question": "What year was actor Anthony Hopkins born?", "answer": "1937", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339320", "question": "What was the name of Bill and Ted's rock band in the movie \"Bill and Ted's Excellent Adventure\"?", "answer": "Wild Stallions", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb0a", "question": "Are pumpkins fruits or vegetables?", "answer": "Fruits", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a931", "question": "What is the only nation that shares a land border with Haiti?", "answer": "The Dominican Republic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb33", "question": "In 1964, who became the first running back in NFL history to rush for more than 10,000 career yards?", "answer": "Jim Brown", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339293", "question": "What 2007 film follows the crew of the Icarus II as they attempt to reignite a falling sun?", "answer": "Sunshine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8f3", "question": "What range contains the world's highest mountains not located in Asia?", "answer": "The Andes", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd2d2ca2596a59cbdfbd393", "question": "What state is also known as the Volunteer State?", "answer": "Tennessee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d47441f8e329de4f87789b", "question": "The Bunya Pine tree is native to which country?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8cc", "question": "What city is home to the eighty-eight storey Petronas Twin Towers?", "answer": "Kuala Lumpur", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefbe546ce05a3942286eed", "question": "Which actor had a role in the Hannibal Lector films \"Manhunter,\" \"Silence of the Lambs,\" \"Hannibal\" and \"Red Dragon\"?", "answer": "Frankie Faison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071d013745b36be73039d3", "question": "Who is credited with inventing the V-2 rocket for Nazi Germany and later the Saturn V rocket for the United States?", "answer": "Wernher von Braun", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ec25cd8dc25ca9e12ef642", "question": "What fraternity do the Lewis and Gilbert join in the 1984 film \"Revenge of the Nerds\"?", "answer": "Lambda Lambda Lambda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c104", "question": "Carbonade Flamande is a dish made with what beverage?", "answer": "Beer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b374", "question": "What was the chief Roman silver coin?", "answer": "Denarius", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abcd", "question": "On which river does the city of Dublin stand?", "answer": "Liffey\u00a0River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c758", "question": "What vitamin, found in carrots, helps maintain the acuity of your vision?", "answer": "Vitamin A", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338927", "question": "What two letters in American Sign Language require a finger movement?", "answer": "J and Z", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c71c", "question": "What \u00adword is the mathematical term for a triangle whose sides are all different lengths?", "answer": "Scalene", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bf5", "question": "What year was actress Julia Roberts born?", "answer": "1967", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c766877e98cb977789cd", "question": "Where is Bohemian Switzerland National Park?", "answer": "Czech Republic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5bfdffbdb668d7dfe168b5bb", "question": "This ancient attempt to transmute base metals into noble metals was called what?", "answer": "Alchemy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff2100131a458464a93c43b", "question": "Sulaco is a port city in which Joseph Conrad novel?", "answer": "Nostromo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ca", "question": "What year did Jean Anouilh write the play \"The Lark\"?", "answer": "1952", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b01e", "question": "What was the name of the Italian cruise ship hijacked by Palestinian terrorists in 1985?", "answer": "Achille Lauro", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ad", "question": "What nationality was Pablo Picasso?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bac0", "question": "While in play, how many players are on a water polo team?", "answer": "7", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4dd5d06d333868d34d701", "question": "In which concentration camp did Anne Frank die?", "answer": "Bergen-Belsen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe73415eec85e375820b22d", "question": "What nickname did Thomas Jonathan Jackson earn during the American Civil War?", "answer": "Stonewall", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339104", "question": "What year marked the premier of Bizet's opera \"Carmen\"?", "answer": "1875", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60136fd7138175489539637d", "question": "Nolan Bushnell, the founder of Atari, is also the founder of what restaurant chain?", "answer": "Chuck E. Cheese -- It is famous for its pizza, animatronic shows, and electronic games - a feature pioneered by Nolan Bushnell.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338be9", "question": "Which instrument does the Leader of an orchestra play?", "answer": "Violin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5c77cf6424f0f7a362efd54d", "question": "In \"The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time\", how many races are there?", "answer": "6", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338921", "question": "Although he is from hell, what symbol does Spawn cling to?", "answer": "A cross", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa3b36c73aa70ea0b70ae5", "question": "What is the earliest known walled city?", "answer": "Fortifications unearthed in Jericho dating back to 6800 B.C. confirm that it is the earliest known walled city.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af81", "question": "What was Paul Revere's profession?", "answer": "Silversmith", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394c7", "question": "What planet was Mork from in the TV show \"Mork & Mindy\"?", "answer": "Ork", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac5c", "question": "What year did the Chernobyl disaster occur?", "answer": "1986", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5be580815415ba52ed6f0ab5", "question": "Approximately, how many seconds comprise a day?", "answer": "86400", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b947", "question": "Which sport did hall-of-famer Larry Bird play?", "answer": "Basketball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc4f", "question": "What year did the iPhone debut on the market?", "answer": "2007", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339660", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Marge's mother?", "answer": "Jacqueline Bouvier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acec", "question": "What Canadian city boasts the world's richest rodeo that was first staged in 1912?", "answer": "Calgary", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd96dbc23c87fd04dd15e2e", "question": "Who wrote the Pledge of Allegiance?", "answer": "Francis Bellamy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5902a04fcad1ec93f27df769", "question": "What is Cask ale sometimes referred to as in the UK?", "answer": "Real ale", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd80", "question": "\"Project Kansas\" was the name for the top secret 1985 attempt to revamp what product?", "answer": "Coca-Cola", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ef", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows\" what does the acronym RAB stand for?", "answer": "Regulus A. Black", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59774376284458f1d7854429", "question": "Who played Spock in the original Star Trek television series?", "answer": "Leonard Nimoy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c884877e98cb977789e7", "question": "What US state shares the shortest border with Canada?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4c4", "question": "Ladin is primarily spoken in which area of the world?", "answer": "Northern Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a78a", "question": "What is the only Canadian Province which borders the Pacific Ocean?", "answer": "British Columbia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c660", "question": "What is the purpose of \"seeding\" a cloud?", "answer": "To create rain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8dc", "question": "The name for this semi-precious stone comes from the Latin for \"sea water\"?", "answer": "Aquamarine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ad9de5ee748bb36357acde5", "question": "Who played Matlock in the muder mystery series of the same name?", "answer": "Andy Griffith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac15", "question": "The Union of the Comoros is located on the northern end of which water channel?", "answer": "Mozambique Channel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b067", "question": "Which Space Shuttle broke apart during re-entry in February, 2003?", "answer": "Columbia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397b9", "question": "What instrument did Don Henley play as a member of Eagles?", "answer": "Drums", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339172", "question": "Mark Hamill was a voice actor for which popular early 90's superhero cartoon?", "answer": "Batman: The Animated Series", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe1f341145fb29466707399", "question": "What candy bar originally came in three pieces and had three different flavors?", "answer": "3 Musketeers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59564403803c1f1ebcc4a033", "question": "Ketchup was sold in the 1830\u2019s as what?", "answer": "Medicine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefa9126ce05a3942286edb", "question": "What classic novel did TV's \"Big Brother\" get its name from?", "answer": "1984", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c41f", "question": "How many eyelids does a cat have on each eye?", "answer": "Three", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395e4", "question": "In The Simpsons, who said: \"Hello, beautiful. No ring, I see. So you are only arranged to be married.\"?", "answer": "Apu Nahasapeemapetilon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a207", "question": "Harvey Lee Yeary became famous under what name?", "answer": "Lee Majors", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd3b97e83c707845b2154", "question": "How many noble houses of Westeros are there in \"Game of Thrones\"?", "answer": "Nine (Arryn, Baratheon, Greyjoy, Lannister, Martell, Stark, Targaryen, Tully and Tyrell)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caf3", "question": "What medical term is used to describe the process of sweating?", "answer": "Hydrosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60173c1044491cbd7c5a17a2", "question": "How did Monday get its name?", "answer": "Moon's day -- It was formerly spelled moned\u00e6i, which comes from the Old English words m\u014dnand\u00e6g and m\u014dnd\u00e6g (\u201cmoon's day\u201d).", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a438", "question": "In what country is the San Andreas Fault located?", "answer": "United States", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7cea1877e98cb97778a44", "question": "Where is the world\u2019s largest known beaver dam?", "answer": "Alberta, Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b1", "question": "Who played the female lead role in the 2007 movie \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Claire Danes", "category": "entertainment"}]